

#### CONTACT

- +91 9930966745
- +91 8090935050
- vikashfromgkp@gmail.com
- Maitry Heights, Virar West Global City Mumbai 401303

#### **SKILLS**

- Web Development
- Project Estimations
- Troubleshooting
- Requirements Gathering
- Bug Resolution
- SDLC
- Project Scoping
- React JS, AngularJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery
- Team Collaboration
- Jira, Git, SVN
- SEO principles
- Debugging proficiency
- Accessibility (WCAG guideline)
- PHP
- Wordpress
- MySQL
- · Accessibility Testing
- Accessibility Development

#### LANGUAGE

- English
- Hindi

### CERTIFICATIONS

- DHS Section 508 Trusted Tester
- WIX Accessibility
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- HTML & CSS

## **VIKASH** SHARMA

# SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & ACCESSIBILITY WEB DEVELOPER

#### **SUMMARY**

With eight years of experience in user interaction design, I create intuitive and engaging interfaces by blending user-centric principles with technical requirements. I ensure high standards of usability and aesthetics for both open-source and proprietary systems. My passion for design and development drives me to craft effective, user-friendly solutions that meet both user needs and project goals.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Sakshi Infotech Solutions LLP

2018 - PRESENT

Sr. Front-End Developer | Accessibility Web Developer

- Improved and expanded project platforms using JavaScript to develop rich user interfaces.
- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Designed Uls within frontend web frameworks such as Bootstrap, WordPress, Google Material Design, HTML, CSS, Media Query, exploiting associated templates and tools to shorten development times.
- Employed End-to-End Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) methodologies during multiple projects, streamlining cross-discipline development
- Accessibility Developer using as per the accessibility standards (Section 508 and WCAG 2.0 and 2.1)

#### **Neebal Technologies**

2015-2018

Associate Software Developer

- Developed software applications to meet customer requirements.
- Analyzed and resolved technical issues related to software development.
- Assisted in the design, development, coding, testing and debugging of software applications.
- Collaborated with other developers and stakeholders on software projects.
- Implemented changes to existing software based on client feedback.

#### **EDUCATION**

2010 - 2013 SRI RAM SWAROOP MEMORIAL

• Master of Computer Application

2006 - 2009 ISLAMIA COLLAGE OF COMMERCE, GORAKHPUR

**GROUP OF PROFESSIONAL** 

• B.Com (Marketing & Accounts)

2004 - 2006 R.I.C. INTER COLLEGE

Intermediate (Science)

2004 - 2004 N.E. RAILWAY BOYS INTER COLLEGE

• High School

#### **PROJECT**

- Sakshi Infotech Solutions
   (www.sakshiinfotechsolutions.com)
- SIS Enable (www.sisenable.com)
- S & M Associates (www.sandmassociates.in)
- Neebal Technologies (www.neebal.com)
- Jeevan Jyoti Trust Hospital (www.jeevanjyotitrusthospital.com)
- Bhuvana Consultancy
   (www.bhuvanaconsultancy.in)
- H2O Works (www.h2oworks.co)
- P.Hirani
   (www.butterflydiamonds.com)
- Internal Project for Mahindra Finance
- Quality Porta
- Email Templates
- Fixed Deposit
- SSO Portal
- E-Saarathi
- Setup HRMS system
- Created PMS system
- CRON job for employee birthday and work anniversary

#### **IGATE Global Solution Ltd**

Project Trainee

• Assisted in the assembly of project documentation, ensuring inclusion of data and preliminary information.

- Learned from and observed experienced colleagues in various roles.
- Enhanced training efficiency by actively seeking guidance and providing thorough feedback, collaborating closely with supervisors and coworkers.
- Efficiently distributed client communication for ongoing project management.

#### Government of Delhi

2013-2014

Data Analyst

- Identified and documented detailed business rules and use cases after analyzing requirements
- Conducted research and resolved data integrity issues in databases
- Created monthly reports utilizing advanced Excel spreadsheet functions.
- Analyzed large datasets to identify trends, patterns and correlations for business insights.

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

- Passport Number: X3434816
- Father's Name: Late Mr. R.D. Sharma
- Gender: Male
- Nationality: Indian
- · Marital Status: Married

2014-2014